Guide to the James Buchanan Duke Papers, 1777-1999 and undated RL.00001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Legal Papers, 1878-1926 and undated (bulk 1910s-1925); 3
  Property deeds, indentures of sale, and other legal documents and correspondence related to property transactions and agreements; documents and clippings related to Lillian N. Duke's 1925 appeal of the 1906 divorce suit between herself and James B. Duke; and miscellaneous contracts and court records. Also present are land plats and architectural plans by Horace Trumbauer and other architects for the properties owned by James B. Duke and indentures related to endowments he established. Several of the property transactions documented involve other members of the Duke family, including Benjamin N. Duke and Sarah P. Duke, Washington Duke, Mary E. [Duke] Lyon, and Mary Duke Biddle.
  - Agreements, court records, indentures, 1897-1925 (Box 15)
  - Property and Houses: Appraisals/Inventories, 1918; 1925-1926; undated (Box 15)
    Inventories and appraisals of personal property at Charlotte, NC (1926), 1 E. 78th St., New York, NY (1918, 1926), and Rough Point, Newport, R.I. (1925)
  - Property and Houses: Somerville, N.J., deed, 1916 (Box 15)
  - Property and Houses: Somerville, N.J., clippings, 1903-1987 (Box 15)
  - Property and Houses: Somerville, N.J.: Blueprints, Duke Farms Co. melon house (proposed) (oversize) (Box 72)
  - Property and Houses: East 85th St., New York, NY, 1906-1912 (Box 15)
  - Property and Houses: 1 East 78th Street, New York, NY, 1913 (Box 15)
    Letter and bill from Frederick Collins to J.B. Duke regarding work performed on house
  - Property and Houses: 1 East 78th Street, New York, NY: Architectural plans by Horace Trumbauer, 1909 (Oversize-folder 4)
  - Property and Houses: 1 East 78th Street, New York, NY, clippings, 1914; 1915; 1978 (Box 15)
  - Property and Houses: 1009 Fifth Ave., New York, NY, 1901-1919; undated (Box 15)
    Includes indentures of sale of property from Benjamin N. Duke and Sarah P. Duke to J.B. Duke (1907), and from J.B. Duke and Nanaline Duke to Mary Duke Biddle (1919); undated inventory of personal property
  - Property and Houses: Charlotte, NC, 1917-1925 (Box 15)
    Includes accounts of money owed by J.B. Duke to Southern Power Company in relation to purchase of the property
  - Property and Houses: Charlotte, NC, clippings, 1966; 1977; 1997-1998 (Box 15)
  - Property and Houses: Charlotte, NC, land plats and blueprints for laundry in residence (oversize), 1919; 1922 (Oversize-folder 3)
  - Property and Houses: Durham, NC: deeds, land plats, indentures, etc., 1878-1907 (Box 15)
    Includes indentures of sale and deeds for property transactions involving James B. Duke and other Duke family members, including Washington Duke, Benjamin N. Duke, and Mary E. [Duke] Lyon
  - Property and Houses: Durham, NC: land plats, Conservatory of Music and Main Street Methodist Episcopal Church (oversize), 1907; 1913 (Box 73)
  - Property and Houses: Miscellaneous, 1901; 1 items (Box 15)
    Cover letter for property deeds: Thomas Hall to Wm. Hall, Wm. Hall to Benjamin N. Duke
  - Estate of Elizabeth L. Roney, 1882-1884; undated (Box 16)
    James B. Duke was executor of Roney's estate. Includes Last Will and Testament, and correspondence related to settling bills
  - James B. Duke v. Lillian N. Duke and Frank T. Huntoon, 1906: On Petition for Divorce, Final Decree, 1906 May 7 (Box 16)
  - Lillian N. Duke v. James B. Duke, 1925: Correspondence, 1925-1926 (Box 16)
    Main correspondents are W. R. Perkins and representatives of the law firm of Miller & Otis. Contains a few copies of court documents that were sent as enclosures.
  - Lillian N. Duke v. James B. Duke, 1925: Court records, published (Box 16)
  - Lillian N. Duke v. James B. Duke, 1925: Court records (Box 16)
  - Lillian N. Duke v. James B. Duke, 1925: Court records, Exhibits, 1905-1906 (Box 16)
  - Lillian N. Duke v. James B. Duke, 1925: Court records, Memorandum, 1907; undated (Box 16)
  - Lillian N. Duke v. James B. Duke, 1925: Research: Legal precedents (Box 16)
  - Lillian N. Duke v. James B. Duke, 1925: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 16)
    Includes the final opinion written by Justice Giegrich and clippings related to the lawsuit
  - Indenture: Cemetery endowment, Alamance County, NC, 1924 (Box 16)
  - Indenture and Deed of Trust establishing The Doris Duke Trust, 1924, December 11, with October 1925 additions, 1924-1925 (Box 16)
- Financial Papers, 1874-1933 and undated (bulk 1900s-1925); 4
  Arranged in descending order according to the hierarchy of the original bookkeeping system, followed by miscellaneous financial records and subject folders.
  Contains documents related to James B. Duke's private and business investments, including ledgers, journals, cashbooks, voucher records, deposit slips, cancelled checks, stock certificates, and account balance worksheets. Also present are expense records for payroll and other costs in the Duke households and offices, including The Duke Endowment. Household and office expenses of Benjamin N. Duke and his family are present to a lesser extent. Miscellaneous business records are scattered throughout. Personal and family expenses are also documented through various orders, invoices and receipts for jewelry, travel, club memberships, automobiles, and other expenses.
  - Ledger No. 1, 1890-1901; 1 Volumes (Box 16)
    Accounts grouped by entity involved with alphabetical index at beginning of volume.
  - Ledger No. 2, 1902-1912; 1 Volumes (Box 17)
  - Ledger No. 3, 1913-1914; 1 Volumes (Box 17)
  - Ledger No. 4, 1915-1920; 1 Volumes (Box 17)
  - Ledger No. 5, 1920-1925; 1 Volumes (Box 18)
  - Journal No. 1, 1890 December-1905 (Box 18)
  - Journal No. 2, 1906 January-1912 (Box 18)
    Accounts grouped chronologically. Numbers next to entity names correspond to page numbers in Ledgers Nos. 1-5
  - Journal No. 3, 1912 December-1914 (Box 19)
  - Journal No. 4, 1915 January-1919 (Box 19)
  - Journal No. 5, 1920 January-1925 October (Box 19)
  - Cashbook No. 1, 1890 December-1901 November (Box 20)
  - Cashbook No. 2, 1902 January-1912 April (Box 20)
  - Cashbook No. 3, 1912 May-1914 December (Box 20)
  - Cashbook No. 4, 1915 January-1918 July (Box 21)
  - Cashbook No. 5, 1918 August-1922 April (Box 21)
  - Cashbook No. 6, 1922 May-1925 October (Box 21)
  - Voucher Records No. 1, 1914 May-December (Box 22)
    Record of itemized expenditures, including office, staff, personal, and residential expenses
  - Voucher Records No. 2, 1915 January-1917 June (Box 23)
  - Voucher Records No. 3, 1917 June-1919 January (Box 24)
  - Voucher Records No. 4, 1919 February-1921 April (Box 25)
  - Voucher Records No. 5, 1921 May-1923 May (Box 26)
  - Voucher Records No. 6, 1923 June-1925 February (Box 27)
  - Voucher Records No. 7, 1925 March-October (Box 28)
  - Cancelled checks, Bankers Trust Co., 1916 March 30-1925 July 10; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Cancelled checks, Farmers' Loan and Trust Co., 1894 October 15-1909 August 9; 4 folders (Box 29)
  - Cancelled checks, Farmers' Loan and Trust Co., 1909 September 2-1924 May 8; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Cancelled checks, Morgan Guaranty Trust Co. of New York, 1912 January 19-1925 June 29; 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Cancelled checks, National Bank of Commerce, 1914 February 25-1925 June 9 (Box 30)
  - Cancelled checks, National City Bank of New York, 1922 January 7-1925 September 2 (Box 30)
  - Cancelled checks, Passbooks, 1907-1919 (Box 30)
  - Deposit Slip Register (J.B. and B.N. Duke), 1918 July-1921 July (Box 31)
    Access Restrictions
  - Deposit Slip Register, 1921 July-1922 June; 1 Volumes (Box 32)
    Mainly payments to the credit of various Duke family members, including Nanaline H. Duke, Doris Duke (via trust), Walker P. Inman, Sarah P. Duke, Mary Duke Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel Biddle, Jr., Angier B. Duke, and Cordelia Biddle Duke. Business expenses scattered throughout.
  - Payroll and other expenses, 1917-1928; 1 Volumes (Box 33)
    Includes transactions with the Estate of James B. Duke, The Duke Endowment, Nanaline H. Duke, Benjamin N. Duke (office and personal), Sarah P. Duke, Mary Duke Biddle, Angier B. Duke
  - Employee Certificates of Residency, NY State Income Tax, 1921-1927 (Box 34)
  - Federal Income Tax, 1920-1925; 6 folders (Box 34)
  - State Income Taxes: Correspondence with Income Tax Bureau, State of New York, 1922; 1926; 4 items (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, invoices, etc., 1878-1917; 11 folders (Box 34)
    Includes invoices, receipts, certificates and scattered correspondence related to stock transactions, loans, business expenses of J.B. Duke and B.N. Duke, and personal xpenses of J.B. Duke and Nanaline Duke, including those for jewelry, travel, club memberships, automobiles, clothing and other purchases.
  - Miscellaneous receipts, invoices, etc., 1921-1925; undated; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous financial statements of James B. Duke (oversize), 1913-1925; undated (Box 74)
  - Trial balances, 1898-1900 (Box 35)
  - Farmers' Loan and Trust Company, NY: Loans and stocks, 1902-1912 (Box 35)
  - Farmers' Loan and Trust Company, NY: Passbook, 1912-1919 (Box 35)
  - First Methodist Episcopal Church, Somerville, N.J.: Deeds, 1874; 1919; 1925; 1928 (Box 35)
  - First Methodist Episcopal Church, Somerville, N.J., 1921-1932; undated; 3 folders (Box 35)
    Contains correspondence, receipts, and scattered financial worksheets related to the establishment of a building fund and the design and construction of the church. Also includes building specifications from architect P.C. Van Nuys and builder's contract (1928) and a building fund analysis for the years 1921-1929 (1929).
  - First Methodist Episcopal Church, Somerville, N.J.: Floor plans (oversize) (Box 73)
  - German-American National Bank of New Orleans: liquidation and final dividends, 1931-1933 (Box 35)
  - Lincoln Hospital, Durham, NC: Endowment, 1905; 3 items (Box 35)
    Letter, receipt and agreement related to transfer of $5000 worth of American Tobacco Company 4% bonds to the Trustees of Lincoln Hospital
  - List of charitable contributions, 1890-1925, undated; 1 items (Box 35)
    List of financial contributions to churches, hospitals, orphanages and homes, YMCA and YWCA, charities, colleges, and unidentified donations
- Estate Papers, 1777-1934 and undated (bulk 1926-1928); 5
  Contains documentation related to the settlement of the Estate of James B. Duke and is divided into four subseries: Correspondence, Legal Papers, Financial Papers, and Printed Material Subseries. Due to Item VI of Duke's will, which provided for a bequest of two million dollars to be divided among extended family members, the bulk of the Correspondence and Legal Papers Subseries consist of letters, legal and genealogical research, affidavits, and other documents related to Item VI claims. Also documented are bequests to various trusts, including the Duke Endowment and the Doris Duke Trust; accounts of James B. Duke's wealth and property at the time of his death; the income earned and taxes levied against ongoing investments and business concerns; and the costs of administering the Estate. Individuals represented in the Estate Papers Series include George G. Allen, Charles Caldwell, Clarence E. Case, Elizabeth Duke, Nanaline H. Duke, William P. Few, Forrest Hyde, C.E. Mapes, William R. Perkins, Alexander H. Sands, James E. Stagg, and Eugene L. Vaughan.
  - Correspondence, 1925-1931; undated; 1
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1925, October-November 30, 3 folders (Box 35)
    - 1925, December-1926, May, 9 folders (Box 36)
    - 1926, June-1927, February, 9 folders (Box 37)
    - 1927, March-August, 7 folders (Box 38)
    - 1927, September-1928, February, 8 folders (Box 39)
    - 1928, March-1931, March, undated, 6 folders (Box 40)
  - Legal Papers, 1777-1928; undated (bulk 1925-1928); 2
    Includes records collected and notes and reports of findings made by Charles Caldwell during his pre-trial research; notes and legal research by executors and attorneys; genealogical charts and other sources of information on the Duke family; reports and correspondence from private investigators and handwriting and document experts; affidavits, completed questionnaires, and related correspondence submitted by claimants; court records including evidence; records for the distribution of the monies under Item VI of the will; and other legal records. The bulk of the court records are related to the Elizabeth Duke et al. (Texas) petition for an Item VI distribution. Inventories of Mr. Duke's personal properties are filed under Receipts for Legacy and Refunding Bonds, 1926. Receipts for specific bequests are filed alphabetically by recipient name.
    - Nanaline Duke et. al. (executors) v. Southern Power Co. (Piedmont Electro-Chemical Co.) and Dillworth Methodist Episcopal Church, South, 1923 October-1927 February; 3 folders (Box 40)
      Correspondence, affidavits, exhibits, court orders and decrees related to claims made against the estate of J.B. Duke.
    - Nanaline Duke et. al. (executors) v. Southern Power Co. (Piedmont Electro-Chemical Co.) and Dillworth Methodist Episcopal Church, South: Cancelled notes transferred in settlement, 1927 February (Box 40)
    - Research: Genealogical "wheel" charts showing kinship to John Roney and Taylor Duke (oversize), circa 1926; 2 charts (Box 73)
    - Research: Legal precedents, circa 1927 (Box 41)
    - Research: Notes on Elizabeth Duke claim, Thomas Duke kinship: (Texas), circa 1927 June (Box 41)
    - Research: Notes on Elizabeth Duke claim, Thomas Duke kinship: (Georgia) (includes affidavits), 1927 June-July (Box 41)
    - Research: Notes on Vaughan claim, Polly (Mary) Duke Vaughan kinship, circa 1927 (Box 41)
    - Research: Notes on Washington Duke, 1927 (Box 41)
    - Research: Report from National Coloniana Society to Executors on the descendents of J.B. Duke and disputed claims, 1927 April (Box 41)
    - Research: Reports and correspondence from expert witnesses, 1928 (Box 41)
    - Research: Sources: Census returns with correspondence, 1800-1870 (1927); 1927-1928; 2 folders (Box 41)
      Certified copies of census listings for Granville County, NC, Orange County, NC and Carroll County, GA, and correspondence with genealogists
    - Research: Sources: Census returns: marked as Ex. "A"-Ex. "V", 1810-1870 (1927) (Box 41)
    - Research: Sources: Census returns: Notes, circa 1927-1928 (Box 41)
    - Research: Sources: Court records, Franklin County, NC (extracts from minutes), 1852-1853 (1927) (Box 41)
    - Research: Sources: Court records, Orange County, NC (with notes), 1753-1856 (1927) (Box 41)
    - Research: Sources: Court records, Orange County, NC: Taylor Duke, 1799-1818 (1927) (Box 41)
    - Research: Sources: Land and property deeds and transfers, 1777-1880 (1927); 1927 (Box 41)
      Mainly records of Orange County [Durham County] property transfers, including transactions involving J.B. Duke, Washington Duke, Benjamin N. Duke, Brodie L. Duke, and Mary E. Lyon, and other known or potential relations
    - Research: Sources: Marriage records and notes: Duke, Stagg, Vaughan, 1783-1927 (Box 41)
    - Research: Sources: Military service records and notes: M. Tillett Harris et. al., 1784 (1927); 1908-1927 (Box 41)
      Includes transcript of interview with M. Tillett Harris regarding his Civil War service and his acquaintance with W. "Bill" Vaughan
    - Research: Sources: Wills and inventories (with notes), 1788-1905 (1927); 1927 (Box 41)
      Includes copies of wills of Washington Duke (1900, 1904), William Duke, Sr. (1839, 1854), and Hardeman Duke (1835)
    - Research: Charles Caldwell: annotated copy of "Determination by the Executors...", 1927 (Box 41)
    - Research: Charles Caldwell: Daily Activity Statements, 1927 May 9-September 13 (Box 41)
    - Research: Charles Caldwell: Reports, 1927-1928 (Box 42)
    - Research: Charles Caldwell: Notes, 1927 June-November; 5 folders (Box 42)
    - Research: Charles Caldwell: Notes, 1927 December-1928 May; undated (Box 42)
    - Research: Charles Caldwell: Expenses and receipts, 1926 July-1928 March; undated (Box 42)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes about Elizabeth Duke's activities, correspondence, and evidence; used to prepare for direct/cross-examination, 1928 January-May; undated (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes regarding exhibits, evidence, expert witnesses, and Elizabeth Duke, 1928 January 18-April 26; undated (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes to prepare for trial on March 24 and 25, 1928 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes by Charles Caldwell regarding exhibits and evidence for trial, 1927 August 22-1928 April 28 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes for and correspondence to Senator Case, pertaining to evidence and trial, 1928 April 21 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes about Elizabeth Duke used to prepare for trial, 1928 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Reports of private investigator on Elizabeth Duke and others, 1927 November 29-December 17 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes on witnesses, 1928 March; undated (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Pretrial conference between lawyers for Estate / Elizabeth Duke (transcript), 1927 November 25 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes on testimonies and affidavits of Dr. Henry M. Dukeand others, 1928, January 20 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes on testimonies and affadavits of John T. and Frances E. Eady, 1928 January 23-24 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes on testimonies (2 folders), 1928 January 23-31 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes on testimony and affidavits of Hattie Gaffield, 1928 January 26 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes on transcript of testimony, pp. 569-1120, 1928 January 25-31 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes from testimonies, 1928, March 15-16; notes in preparation for March 16 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes from testimony with Charles Caldwell's notes made during trial, 1928 March 19-22 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes from testimony by W. R. Perkins, including notes on evidence, 1928 March 22-26 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Pre-trial records: Interrogatories, 1928 April (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes on testimonies of George G. Allen, August Harkhorn, Stewart L. Hawkins, C.E. Mapes, 1928 May 21 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Notes on testimonies, undated (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Names of claimants presenting claims through E. Duke, 1927 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Charles Duke kinship (Georgia), 1928 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: David Duke kinship (Georgia and Miss.), 1926-1928 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: David and Thomas Duke kinship and affiliation with Primitive Baptist Church, affidavits, 1927 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: David Duke kinship, 1927 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Robert Duke kinship, 1926 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Thomas Duke kinship: affidavits, 1926-1927 (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Thomas Duke kinship: affidavits, 1927; 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Thomas Duke kinship: affidavits, 1927-1928; 4 folders (Box 44)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Thomas Duke kinship: (Primitive Baptist), affidavits and evidence, 1927 (Box 44)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Thomas Duke kinship: (Primitive Baptist), affidavits and interviews, 1927 (Box 44)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Misc. affidavits, 1926-1928 (Box 44)
    - Elizabeth Duke claim: Affidavits relating to her evidence, 1927-1928 (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: List of descendants, undated (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Executor's questionnaires and affidavits (disallowed claims), 1925-1927; 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Statement by Eugene Lee Vaughan, 1926 June 22 (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Statement of evidence submitted by E.L. Vaughan, 1926 October 18 (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Evidence submitted by E.L. Vaughan, 1926 (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Statement on behalf of E.L. Vaughan, setting forth the grounds of his claim, with affidavits, 1927 April 18; 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Recapitulation of the facts on which E.L. Vaughan bases his claim, 1927 May 5 (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Notes about claims and evidence, undated (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Affidavits, A-W, 1925-1927; undated; 3 folders (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Tillett Harris's affidavits, records of questioning, pension records, 1927; undated (Box 44)
    - Vaughan claim: Last will and testament of James Vaughan ( 1788, October 26), undated (Box 45)
    - On Petition for Decree of Distribution of $2 million under Item VI of [ J.B. Duke's] Will, Decree of Distribution, 1927 November (Box 45)
    - On Petition for Decree: Order of Adjournment, 1927 November 25 (Box 45)
    - On Petition of Edward Lee Vaughan for reopening case, etc.; Order, 1928 January 6 (Box 45)
    - On Petition for Decree: Order, 1928 January 6 (Box 45)
    - On Petition for Decree: Trial transcript, 1928 January 6 (Box 45)
    - On Petition for Decree: Trial transcript [Elizabeth Duke claim], 1928 January 20; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - On Petition for Decree: Trial transcript [Elizabeth Duke claim], 1928 Jan 23.-25; 1 Volumes (Box 45)
    - On Petition for Decree: Trial transcript [Elizabeth Duke claim], pp. 557-1835, 1928 January 25-31; March 15-22; 1 volume and 10 folders (Box 46)
    - On Petition for Decree: Trial transcript [Elizabeth Duke claim], pp. 1836-2151, 1928 March 16-26; 1 Volumes (Box 47)
    - On Petition of Decree of Distribution: Order, 1928 May 21 (Box 47)
    - Clippings: Item VI of J.B. Duke's will, Elizabeth Duke claim, court hearings, 1927-1928 (Box 47)
    - Evidence: Index to P series and E.D. series (with notes), 1928 (Box 47)
    - Evidence: P series: P 1-2, undated (Box 47)
    - Evidence: P series: P 3, 6-40, 1926-1928; undated (Box 47)
    - Evidence: P series: P 41-60, 1866-1928; undated (Box 47)
    - Evidence: P series: P 61-81, 1801-1928 (Box 47)
    - Evidence: P series: P 82-91, 95-96, 1861-1928; undated (Box 47)
    - Evidence: P series: P 98, 1894-1928 (Box 47)
    - Evidence: P series: P 100, undated (Box 48)
    - Evidence: P series: P 102-123, 1861-1928; undated (Box 48)
    - Evidence: P series: P 130-140, 1861-1928; undated (Box 48)
    - Evidence: P series: P 141-159, 161, 1866-1928; undated (Box 49)
    - Evidence: P series: P 126-129, 1928 (Box 49)
    - Evidence: P series: P 160, pp. 1-38, 1928; 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Evidence: P series: P 160, pp. 1-38, 1928; 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Evidence: pages from church books (photographs and photostats), 1928; 2 folders (Box 49)
      Photographs of church records, many with segments cut out (possibly used to construct evidence exhibits)
    - Evidence: E.D. series: E.D. 1-5, 1928 (Box 49)
    - Evidence: E.D. series: E.D. 6, 7, 20, 26, 1928 (Box 50)
    - Evidence: E.D. series: E.D. 13-14, 18-19, 21-23, 1928 (Box 50)
    - Determination by the Executors of James B. Duke, Deceased, of Those Entitled to Participate in the Distribution Made Under Item VI..., 1927 (Box 50)
    - Determination by the Executors: Final awards, circa 1926-1928 (Box 50)
    - Determination by the Executors: Schedule of Disallowed Claims, circa 1927-1928 (Box 50)
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, John Taylor, kinship through: (Executors' questionnaires), 1927 (Box 50)
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, John Taylor, kinship through: James A. Duke, Martha Angeline Duke Moore (affidavits), 1926 (Box 50)
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, John Taylor, kinship through: Lida Duke Angier, Pattie Duke Moore (affidavits), 1926-1928 (Box 50)
    - Claims (allowed): Duke, John Taylor, kinship through: Nannie Duke Wyant, Maude Duke Karnes Stuart (affidavits), 1926-1927 (Box 50)